I think the the big test though is going
to be around product quality. It's much
easier to build apps than than ever
before without a doubt. Five years ago,
you could give a founder $20 million to
hire engineers and they can go hire all
the best engineers and if they don't
have great product intuition and product
taste and like a process for building a
great product, then they're just going
to light $20 million on fire, right?
Like it's it's not going to matter. The
phase that we're in now is the number of
high quality apps is still bottlenecked
by like product taste and judgment.
And part of what I'm personally excited
about is ways in which we can use AI to
make people better at creating products.
Hello, [snorts] I'm your host David
Bernard and with me today, Revenue Cat
CEO Jacob Iding. Our guest today is
Andrew Maguire, managing partner at
Vololo Ventures, an early stage venture
capital firm investing in preede and
seedstage startups founded by
exceptional builders. On the podcast, we
talked with Andrew about the
bootstrappers path to 10 million in ARR,
what's actually investable in consumer
in 2026,
and why product taste is the new
bottleneck, not engineering. Hey Andrew,
thank you so much for joining us on the
podcast today.
>> Hey David, thanks for having me back.
>> And Jacob, nice to have you.
>> I'm also here on the podcast, David.
It's good to be here.
>> I forgot to uh say hi to Jacob on the
last podcast, so we were just joking
about that. But anyways, Andrew, super
excited to have you back on. And I
wanted to kick things off with just your
perspective as an investor in consumer
businesses. So, so you're probably one
of the few investors I know anyway that
operated a subscription app, a consumer
subscription app, and is now doing
venture. So, just started at a super
high level like how how are you thinking
about consumer these days and
investability and things like that and
we'll we'll kind of chase those threads.
>> Yeah, sure. In general, I think it's
just a super exciting time, right?
because what we can do uh with AI is so
compelling compared to what was possible
even a few years ago. I think what I'm
seeing from an investor perspective is
obviously like tons of founders are
chasing the enterprise right like these
are big markets like big opportunities a
lot of attention is going there but I
think it's very intuitive to me and
probably to you guys as well that you
know the way that we build consumer
products is going to change a ton with
AI and become much more powerful much
more personalized so I'm very excited
about that I think there's a ton
opportunity. You know, there are
definitely like some some things to
avoid along along the way if you're, you
know, depending on what kind of business
you're trying to build, but generally
speaking, I think it's a super exciting
time for a consumer.
>> Yeah, we were just talking before uh we
hit record about Jacob's got an open
claw setup. I have a Hermes set up. Like
the actual act of building a consumer
app these days is is just light years
different than it was even 12 months
ago. And then that's just on the
building side. And then kind of what you
were alluding to, the kind of
experiences we can now build with AI is
just a a whole new ball game. And I I I
do feel like, you know, gosh, we're 18
years into the app store, but it feels
like a whole new beginning with these AI
capabilities of building all new
experiences and all new apps and all new
opportunities. you know, you guys are
publishing this data on how many apps
are getting posted to the app store and
you know, obviously a lot of them are
using revenue cap, which is awesome. I
think the the big test though is going
to be around product quality, right?
It's much easier to build apps than than
ever before, without a doubt. But I was
sort of thinking the other day about how
like, you know, five years ago, you
could give a founder $20 million to hire
engineers and they can go hire all the
best engineers and if they don't have
great product intuition and product
taste and like a process for building a
great product, then they're just going
to light $20 million on fire, right?
Like it's it's not going to matter. And
so I think the phase that we're in now
is the number of highquality apps is
still bottlenecked by like product taste
and judgment.
And part of what I'm personally excited
about is
ways in which we can use AI to make
people better at creating products,
right? is like I don't think the oneshot
app is going to
really work long term
>> just going to rise above right it's
tough to like not deal in anecdotes
because I think every individual's like
slice of like what apps are you using
right is very is very hard are there any
apps that have entered your guys'
personal lives in the last 18 months
that you can be like oh this was vibe
coded there's one that I can think of
I'm gonna plug I don't know if we've
talked about on the podcast yet is ATC
which is a really cool app if you
haven't tried. It's like it's like an
iteration on watching listening to air
traffic control. It's built by a very
very small team. I know for certain it
was like very vibe not vibecoded but
very AI assisted and is a good example
of like how how you know certainly with
the the ambition of that project
wouldn't have been achievable preai and
just now but but again it's like they
probably could have done that before
the current world because like yeah to
some degree almost the money the money
and the engineers were is expensive but
it was like attainable right versus
versus the taste and intuition to build
a really great product. I don't know if
you can you can't necessarily like go to
Sand Hill Road and like get that right.
It's a more rare thing. I'm I'm
constantly going back and forth on like
where the actual new bottleneck is. I I
initially I was not on this board on the
board of like oh it's like we're we have
like a taste product understanding
bottleneck. I thought that was like a
lot of like sort of elitism uh and
thinking that like it mattered that
much. But the the the reason I've moved
on that is that I think the noise has
gone up so much and like there's just so
many options now that like almost the
way the only way to differentiate is by
having something that's like stands out.
One it's a great product but two then
you know to to really grow you know your
quality of your product will drive down
your cost of acquisition which will then
like ultimately
like ultimately like allow you to reach
more efficiently a larger scale. Another
way to think about this is is if you if
you're a pre-product market fit company,
more engineers is not necessarily going
to accelerate your path to product
market fit, right? There are just so
many different like product decisions
and design decisions and like are you
talking to users and are you are you
doing all this sort of stuff? I think
vibe coding is going to be very
successful and certainly like if you do
have good product intuition, it's going
to make you so much faster, right? I
mean, that's that's where I think the
most the most leverage is right now.
What I'm more skeptical of is the like
oneshot the app type approach. I think
>> just like turning your open claw on and
being like come up with app ideas and
publish them. You don't think that's
going to like make a
>> or like you know like build me build me
a great personalized fitness app and
like here's a couple other sentences
because there's just too many decisions
to make,
>> right?
>> So,
>> well, I don't It's like AI is good at
making decisions. It's the like it's the
again it's a stupid word taste. It's
just like it doesn't know it doesn't
know what information to actually
consider versus not that exists you know
if the context is not exquisitly
prepared in text for it. This is was a
very hard time
>> to kind of like understand that and like
>> okay so like I have certainly seen AI in
my work come up with novel ideas like
that is not that is not I didn't know I
didn't know if that were the case like
12 months ago 24 months ago like oh can
AI not just like regurgitate things it's
already seen it does seem like at least
in terms of novelness coming from like
the recombination of existing factors
right which which is like a big part of
creativity, right? But like I still am
not sure that it knows how to like
choose the best, you know, it can come
up with eight ideas. I as I asked like
app ideas yesterday from AI and it was I
think it was Chad GBT55, but like
honestly I was really impressed. I was
like, "Oh, like two of these five are
really great, but like they're not
really great but have potential." Like
aren't the d I've heard a lot of app
pitches in my life. Like so I have some
like two of them I was like, "Oh, those
are actually like that's viable, right?
It's not just like a personal CRM or
whatever, but it still I don't know if
it has like and I I do think it goes
down to like the the drive, intuition,
taste to like pick one, actually drill
into it, actually like
have conviction to like and I guess this
is where the human and the exceptional
human like still plays a a huge role,
which is like when when the agent the
model doesn't spit out the exactly great
product the first time, they sort of
have the like the missing factors to
look beyond that to like solve the
bottlenecks and stuff. I think the I
think the um the question I'm still in
some ways grappling with is just like
how do these like competitive dynamics
change what it means to like even I
guess from a cash perspective invest in
the app store or in apps and like
consumer and I think there's also David
you kind of brushed over at the
beginning but there's I think a big
difference between like consumer and
like app store consumer or CSS right
like the like we talked you're talking
about Zo Computer and and and uh and
Hermes and OpenClaw and like those are
all consumer products, right? But
they're not like app store products
necessarily, right? Um there is a bit of
a difference and I think it's worth
differentiing. I've seen a lot of
consumer investors actually kind of
pivoting away from the like oh like app
store as this like primary software
delivery thing and like sort of
broadening like Chad GBT is a consumer
product. It's one of the most successful
consumer products in history. It is on
the app store, but I would not consider
it like an app store, right? Like it's
in part in part an app store story. When
you asked like what apps have you
adopted recently that are vibecoded, I I
was like flipping through like the first
few pages of my iPhone, like thinking,
okay, what what what examples do I have?
Zero vibecoded, but multiple AI
assisted. But it's kind of to your
point, the three I came up with were
Whisper Flow, which is is kind of more
B2B, but is an incredible consumer. I'm
paying 20 bucks a month for it,
>> ChatBT, and Claude. It's And those
vibe coded might be wrong cuz like they
might actually be
>> good examples of the initial deployment
of VIP,
>> you know? I think it's just back on this
this whole VI vibe coding thing. I was
talking about taste and judgment. I
think it's also just like a point of
view, right? Like there are so many
different little product decisions that
go into making an app. Like we so we
have a portfolio company called X1 and
it's a it's basically a vibe coding app
but instead of trying to oneshot the app
what they do is they break down every
component of the app creation process
and they figure out like what are the
actual decisions that you need to make
throughout the course of onboarding or
throughout the course of you know like
major features or throughout the course
of like figuring out your brand and
design. And the reason that I like this
is I mean one it just makes it much
easier to like maintain an app over time
because you have these like you know
discrete modular parts of the app that
you can go and adjust but also I think
there's this opportunity to educate
people on how to create products like
these are the sorts of decisions that
you should be thinking about like now
that we bring the cost of of actually
building down so low if tools can really
guide people through the critical
decisions. Not necessarily make them for
them or maybe give them like here's what
we would recommend, but like actually
force the app creator to wrestle with
like a hard question around tradeoffs,
right? like that I think is is the path
to getting from you know apps built
faster with clawude or cursor or
whatever to like a vi like a vibecoded
app that a non-technical person can
actually make you know app store ready
and scalable.
>> Yeah. I mean we did this since you know
this has been a big part of ready catch
stick. It's like we're a billing
infrastructure, but then like you know
this podcast like a lot of what we do is
about actually like how to educate folks
on on monetization and the the practice
more so than like the technology at
least like outwardly facing which is
true. It's unknown exactly what
direction the model companies are going
to take it, but so far both OpenAI and
Enthropic and and to some degree most of
the other ones have have intentionally
out of like safety reasons basically
made these models very like you
mentioned point of view. They've kind of
intentionally coded out the point of
view like they don't want them to have a
point of view that would be like
unaligned, right? actually sometimes in
their attempt to align or give make them
not have a point of view, it in fact
gives them a point of view, right? Which
is like hyper neutrality or an attempt
at hyperneutrality, but that's sort of
by design. And so like will we ever get
to the point where an agent or like a
model like isn't designed that way is
designed I've never seen but I've heard
I don't know if this is true but they
say like when a model comes out of
pre-training so they have this like
pre-training step where they just like
gobble down the entire internet and then
you have this RHF step where like they
they basically give it Chad GBT style
questions and then they like they give
it a reward if it answers them in a good
way and then they retrain the model
based on that. So these like two phases
and I've heard like once the when the
pre-train gets done the model just
sounds kind of like forgive the phrasing
but like a schizophrenic like somebody
is just like sort of babbling and crazy.
So there's a lot of rawness to it. The
intelligence is in there but like it's
very raw. And so like I think the model
companies actually kind of have a lot of
control on sort of like how these things
end up expressing themselves. And so
like long path to kind of go like I
don't know if that's forever if that's
even a limitation that these things
don't have a point of view. Now, an
entire model that has a single point of
view about fitness apps or something
doesn't seem like all that, you know,
all that useful to the world. So, I
don't know if they would ever build it
with the current flavor of the way these
models are built. It doesn't feel like
they're going to subsume sort of like
the human impetus to build things, which
I think is where which is where like
outlier consumer stuff comes from.
>> Yeah. The point on neutrality is
interesting because it's like it's kind
of like this idea, you know, it's like
there's no such thing as objective
history, right? It's like
>> Right. Yeah. It's written by the it's
whatever's in the training set which is
written by the victors, right?
>> Everything that's Yeah. Everything
that's evaluation is like a point of
view. I think
>> I think they've actually done a pretty
good job. I think it's actually what
makes the models kind of annoying to
work with sometimes is like they're just
so milktoast and like unopinionated or
like
anodine is maybe the right word. I don't
know. They just make these like points
that are like kind of obvious and they
feel like they've discovered something
very critical, like very important when
you talk to them. And it's like, okay,
this doesn't work. That's fine for my
private conversation with Claude, but
like for a marketplace, like an app
store, like people aren't going to be
like, oh my gosh, yes, what an
observation. Let me download this app
and make it part of my life. That's just
it's not going to work with humans at
scale. I think it's like Yeah, I think
it's more about the intelligence and the
context to help unlock like a human
point of view. I think that's that's
sort of a way that I would think about
it.
>> And the more that we can have the more
that we can use AI to accomplish that,
>> then I that gets interesting. And I
think this is kind of the big question
hanging in the air as to whether like
consumer mobile goes away and just gets
subsumed by the big model players
because like there there's a path that
some people predict that like you know
Open AI will just be your everything app
and so you want to track your fitness.
you just say like, "Hey, I'm working out
and I want a good plan." And it
generates your plan and it tracks your
everything. And like it it's hard for me
to take that big of a leap. But to your
like reinforcement learning point,
Jacob, I was actually talking to
somebody from one of the model companies
when I was out in San Francisco for WWC
and asking them like, you know, why why
why
aren't the models better at animations
and taste and things like that? And you
know, can't you just train on like all
the apps of the app store? And then, you
know, does that mean that that these
models can just spit out like the best
apps ever? And and you know, they said
something obvious in hindsight, but
actually quite insightful is like
garbage in, garbage out. Like you can't
just train on everything. Like you you
need
>> Yeah. There's a lot that goes into
selecting what's in the training sets,
right? And I don't
>> and what they need is I mean this is
what Anthropic has done so well with the
the taste of its model and like why it's
better at writing than other models and
has a better personality is they have
like they they have psychologists and
and great writers and others in that
reinforcement learning step in order to
help guide the model to be more
personable to be more empathetic to
write better to all these things. And so
in that conversation and just generally
I don't think it's a big focus of the
model companies today to get a bunch of
like mobile product people into a room
and like have them doing RL but it may
get to the point where they start doing
more of that and and and
>> as they go that direction it will at
least get better. I don't I don't think
it
>> I still have a really hard time seeing a
future of like nonhuman in the loop
building really fantastic great values.
Yeah. I mean,
>> but I think it'll get better.
>> Yeah. Like I look at some of the some of
some some apps we've gotten to know,
especially in the fitness space, like
ladder, gravel, like there's some really
good and I think what makes them really
great, the products are good. Like I've
used many or all of them. Different
strokes, different folks. They do things
differently and then that opinion is
like something people like, but there's
a lot of brand involved too. It's like
Coca-Cola. I mean I don't want to it is
not Coca-Cola and Pepsi because I think
there's more differentiation in these
apps but like to some degree it becomes
you know what is the association what is
the brand who are the people behind it
more so than exactly like the features
like all of these apps will tend to have
a comparable set of features at the
limit. I don't know if this is right
right analogy, but there's a lot of like
classified websites that aren't
Craigslist, right? It doesn't have to
come down to the features because
Craigslist is Craigslist. There's a lot
of soda companies that aren't Coca-Cola,
right? It just comes down to it comes
down to a lot of factors besides like
exactly what it does. Andrew, what what
are you using for your fitness apps
these days?
>> I use
Straa
>> still. Still like a 15y old app or older
like Straa from like the late 2000s.
>> This is the power of utility, right?
Strava andchess.com. I might be like uh
40year subscribers to those apps.
>> That's that's almost a more interesting
bare case for the for consumer software
investment and sort of dynamism than
anything else because it's like is
chess.com ever going to be replaced or
need to be replaced?
>> No. Because but this I mean it's this is
the power of network effects.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right. Would I mean I guess like
I mean I'm putting you spot. Would you
ever invest in like a new like I've got
a chess I've got a new chess app that
I'm building that I think's going to
>> No, but I would be a customer of one,
>> right? So I think
>> invest with your time. Just not your
LP's money.
>> I need more integration capabilities
from vibe coding tools to be able to do
it
>> because you I need to use
>> shipapp.com. Oh, will you will you be my
>> will you be my partner?
>> I'll walk you. I'll help you. You know,
I'll I'll probably work with my friend
Claude, but like uh but I'm sure we can
get you there.
>> This But this brings up a this brings up
a great point, right? So like network
effects, that's where a ventured back
business makes sense. But there's
probably like a bunch of chess apps that
I would pay for as a customer that could
like bootstrap and build $10 million a
year businesses, right? Solving some
niche problem. And to me that's an
extremely exciting use case for the app
store right now just like
>> yeah it gets to the question about like
capital basically and like different
types of capital what the risk profile
is and like what the right funding
mechanism is and we've talked about this
I think probably since the beginning of
revenue cap when revenue started like it
was much more common to see venture
capital style investments into early
stage apps right
>> I I don't I don't know if you would
challenge this, but it definitely feels
like 10 years on it's much less common
than it was
>> 100%.
>> Right. And and and the reason is very
simple. It's it's a recurring revenue
problem.
>> Yeah.
>> Returns high,
>> right? For most of these, right? Maybe
to some degree. I think the expectation
on outliers was higher. Like we there
were a few cases of some like early you
chess.com might be that Straa's in that
example like companies that really
reached like venture scale. Maybe there
was some overestimation on how easy that
was or how common that would be. Maybe
that some of them I wouldn't say stalled
out but like some of them got stuck at
like small small public scale you know I
don't know
>> the hundred billion dollar like the
hundred billion dollar company
>> you know that
>> has yet to exist right in the in the
consumer level
>> or or it's like you know I mean there's
there's the handful of you know like Tik
Tok and social products. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But literally a handful there's
like 10 less than 10. five maybe. I
don't know where like Duelingo's market
cap is today, but it's probably in the
single low double digit billions I would
think.
>> Yeah, it's like four to five.
>> Yeah. Which is venture backable, but not
maybe not as easy in 2026. Like you went
with the hundred billion dollar
outcomes, right?
>> But there has never been a better time
to like
indie developer a $10 million app,
>> right?
>> Yeah. like
>> what you can build
>> they'll like out of like everything that
revenue cat offers to like on the
infrastructure side and then like okay
paid UA use RC capital for working
capital
>> pole forward
>> and like build really high quality niche
products
>> and some of them will break out and
cross a 10 million a year threshold and
then cross a 100 million a year
threshold.
>> Yeah. But if you think about the dynamic
before, right? Like in order to build
company, you needed to raise venture.
>> And then the VCs are going to be like,
how are you going to disrupt chess.com's
network effects? You're not going to be
able to.
>> So then you can't raise that money. And
so then like you can't
>> or you can raise like a very small
amount. Like maybe you can get like a
preede seed if you really try hard.
>> Yeah. May maybe. But now like there's a
very clear lane to build those products
super cash efficiently.
And I think, you know, as the tools for
like making these product decisions get
better, I think that's going to be
really exciting.
>> I think this is a pattern in
capitalism just generally and this is
we're seeing it in software which is
like when a new field emerges often the
input costs are very very high. The
returns are also very very high. So you
can attract this class of capital which
venture capital is not it's not like a
modern modern concept at the scale it is
it's very modern but there you know you
can go back to like the duchies India
India companies like these like trade
companies in the 18 or like whatever
1600s it's like the first kind of
venture where you would raise money and
go like try to make a bunch of money
back which doesn't exist anymore either
like venture capital like how whatever
form it comes in is a transient like
phenomenon in an industry where it's
like underdeveloped costs are high it's
very speculative but when an industry
develops and like cost inputs change
it's like both the reward and the like
requirement drift and like that capital
I'm curious Andrew if you agree with
this is like that feels like the capital
at least in the last couple years has
has drifted to the AI buildout like
basically every venture capital dollar
just about needs to be directly in the
AI buildout or attached very direct like
close to that for two for one That's
probably where the outside returns are
going to come from in the next 5 years.
But then also to your point, the need's
just not there. Like I don't think
anybody can come to you and say like,
"Hey, I need $10 million for my for my
chess.com alternative because it's like
why?" Like you you don't you actually
don't need that.
>> We've been dancing around it a bunch,
but I mean I do want to get your take,
Andrew, directly on like what is
investable in consumer in 2026. For me
it's like you need to have a credible
path to building a low churn product,
right? So like network effects utility
and in some senses are the same. I think
it's probably much easier to build a
really great utility product in the age
of AI because AI can use personal data
so much more effectively and it can get
so much better over time. So like that's
one lane that I think I think
>> this used to be a very elusive thing,
right? It used to be very elusive. I
mean, it was sort of talked about, but
like is it really like
>> to actually build that was very
challenging.
>> Thinking about a product that is going
to be much better for the user in 2
years or 3 years than it is when they
first started using it. Not because of
the promise of like more features being
shipped, right? But because of the usage
lock. Yeah. Usage lock in. I was talking
to somebody on Twitter about picture
this. It's like a plant identifier app.
And somebody was talking trash.
Basically the counterpoint to what
you're saying, Andrew, which is like,
why would you pay for this utility? All
it does is identify plants, but I'm a
daily active. I have a big plants
growing at my house that I'm monitoring
and like I have years of data in this
stupid little app, but I'm like a DAU
probably forever now, which to your
point is like turn combative, right?
Well, and think about like some like
anything around health or anything
around finances. Like the like these
things, these topics that are very
dynamic, there's always new data,
there's always like adjustments that can
be made. Anything where you would say to
yourself, if I had a personal full-time
coach for this thing that had access to
100% of the information, that would be
immensely valuable. like a personal
nutritionist who actually knew
everything that I ate and like knew
everything that was in the kitchen or
whatever or like and then can see the
the record over time and like learn your
strengths and weaknesses and like like
how to encourage it like the actual like
really deep personalization that I think
it if like before historically I think
it's felt like it was a lot of work to
try to get that as a user and even then
it wasn't that good but I feel now it
could be really good. And so I think
companies that demonstrate that and lock
people in that way. Like the utility
piece is going to be forever changed.
Network effects are always going to be
really powerful. They're really really
hard to create. You need to probably
start with utility to get to network
effects, right? Because like you need
some way to jumpstart the network. In
the age of AI though, it's a little bit
complicated because you also have
inference costs. When Facebook first
took off, it was like there was a lot of
infrastructure costs. So maybe it's it's
and then those came down over time. So
it's kind of comparable to that. But I
suspect that it's even more expensive
now. Like if you have a very like
inferenceheavy product,
>> it's easier to consume, right? Like
Facebook Yeah.
>> Facebook needed that inference or needed
that like data center built out because
they had so much users, right? But
before you had users, the cost was low.
But now it's like even to get off the
ground like the the cost per user is I
think much higher than it was during the
Facebook time. They just had like much
bigger scale because it was a free
product
>> and we don't even see the labs are just
absorbing enormous amounts of that,
right?
>> So yeah, they're subsidizing. I mean LPS
are right. Like basically the investors
in in those labs are eating a lot of
that cost now. Yeah,
>> we're struggling not struggling but like
revenue cat is integrating a lot of AI
features now and even we're you know
having to be like well there's cost
decisions that go into these things
right and even at our scale especially
for like speculative features like oh
would this be valuable to a user can we
afford to do this for every user every
day and we're not talking about like
crazy stuff but if we wanted to make one
LLM call like per app per day that would
be like tens of thousands of dollars a
month right like that's a non-trivial
investment for like
>> a small fee Sure. You know I
>> But it will come down.
>> It will come down.
>> Will it? I hope so.
>> Yeah,
>> it may get worse before it gets better
though.
>> Yeah, I know. Yeah, Opus has not come
down in 6 months. So, like I'm a little
bit like skeptical right now, but
nobody's nobody's made a comparable
model to Opus, right? Like I 55 is
comparable, but it's not quite the same.
>> So, like there seems to be enough enough
differentiation that they can maintain
price power. I had this thought the
other day where I was like, you know,
because part of the discussion now is
well use, you know, a dumber model for a
simpler task and, you know, do all that
sort of like routing and stuff. What my
experience has been when I've done that,
I'm like once you taste the good model
like I can't
>> I want to use it for everything.
>> I can't Yeah. I can't because it will
still it will still sometimes screw up
even trivial task and I'm like I just
don't trust I don't trust the outcome or
like it makes mistakes. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And so I do want the best model for
everything, which is really expensive.
But at some point, you know, it will it
will become true that,
>> you know, a more basic cheaper model is
sufficient for a lot of the stuff. I
just I'm not sure we're actually there
yet. You can use CPUs as like maybe a a
crude analogy to this which is where
like you know for the period of 1987 to
19 or to 20110 like every CPU bump was
so critical and important and you always
got the fastest CPU because it really
mattered. But then in the 2010s it kind
of became that all CPUs were pretty much
fast enough and like it became like a
much less interesting differentiator. So
at some point we will be so saturated on
other bottlenecks or whatever that it
won't matter anymore. But but yeah, I
mean we as soon as Fable came out like
two weeks or whatever that was for the
brief period it was out like I upgraded
all my birth because I was like yeah
I'll pay twice as much. I don't do that
many queries for my for my like for like
my high intent like you know stuff for
like my open call running I'm not going
to put that on the highest and most
expensive model just for price reasons.
Backing up I have to agree that like
price will come down. We'll build more
data centers. the current technologies
we're not even like super like we've not
even gotten super efficient on how we do
inference today. There's a lot of
optimizations that can be made yet.
>> So between like just capacity
improvements, other smart optimizations
like the the price and and just like
>> basic economics, right? Like models are
amazing but they're not actually that
that differentiated, right? The only
company that it seems like right now
it's like Nvidia, TSMC, and ASML are
like the only companies that have like
unreplicable technology in this stack.
The models themselves seem like, you
know, get a big this is
oversimplification, but you get big pile
of data, you pre-trade over it, you RLHF
it, you'll get something, right? It's
like,
>> well, that's why they're so that's why
they're so focused on finding
differentiated data now. That becomes
the thing. I I think you're both right
that it will eventually come down. But
when you're making a financial bet, you
also have to be right about timing. And
so if you're going with Fable, you know,
rumors are it might come back this week.
And if you're building your business
around Fable and it takes five years to
get a Fable level model at more
reasonable prices, that's a very
different business outcome than a Fable
level model in two years, in 18 months.
and guessing at that time horizon that
that's what so many people are doing
right now is we're doing it at
RevenueCat like we're using Opus 48 for
our Rico product. It is amazing. I have
been shocked at how good it is at those
things but we're making a bet that like
that will get cheaper but how quickly
will it get cheaper and then how's the
usage going to go and like everything
killed us. We were we were starting to
build some like cost control measures
and I was like like that's what the
venture capital was for, right? It's
like
that's what I was just about to say like
this is this is where venture capital is
actually useful. Like if so if if you
are building a business with network
effects, let the VCs bet on the fact
that the cost of inference will come
down if it's expensive, but like people
are addicted to a product that's
essentially growing virally or
something. Like that's the use case to
go get the venture funding to be like,
okay, we have an amazing product. People
are totally addicted to it. It's growing
super super fast. However, like there
are these like really high variable
costs right now and everyone believes at
some point they'll come down and like as
long as we're growing keep you know
pumping money. Yeah, I mean this is the
bet that the model the core model
company I mean the biggest venture round
private investment rounds of human
history by far margin because of that
exactly like they all understand like
the winnings I mean that's the that's
the other aspect Andrew to that to the
you know go get the venture capital if
you have these like cost of scaling
things the eventual prize has to be big
enough because these folks want to make
money I imagine this is a as an investor
making money is important to you is that
would you say that's fair
>> yeah I mean that's uh LPS tend to care
about that Yeah. So, so LPS, that's
another thing. Did you know this? I
think probably everybody knows this.
Maybe not. But like, so this is when you
invest, it's all of your money, right?
It's like Andrew's personal money that
you invest.
>> No. Is that not true?
>> No.
>> Whose money are you investing?
>> LP's money.
>> Yeah.
>> LPs. What's an LP? Limited partner.
>> Limited partner. Yeah. You raise a
venture fund from people who invest in
the fund. They want to invest in
startups, but they aren't experts at
that. So, they invest in a fund instead.
The fund invests in the startups
and so it goes. I did not know that when
I raised my first my first venture
investment, by the way. I did not fully
understand that damage.
>> A little bit. I kind of sort of, but
like didn't really understand.
>> The ALPs in 2026 are seeing the SpaceX
outcomes. They're seeing the anthropic
and the open air.
>> Yeah. Well, they've seen the last three
anthropic rounds and they're like, "Why
am I doing seed investing? Why don't I
just try as hard as I can to get my and
3x my money in this like megaanthropic
round?" Like that's the facts on the
ground right now. I think it's probably
affecting every stage of venture right
now. Like I would say even early stage
is just being like why the hell don't I
just write into the next OpenAI round,
but that might be over actually.
>> Well, I I also So there's this other I
mean this is getting like a little in
into the weeds on venture, but like
there's also this multi-layer SPV thing
that happened, right? Which is like
okay, yeah, sure. I want to invest in
anthropic, but turns out I don't know
Daario. Probably not getting on the cap
table, but I can invest in some fund
that invested in a fund that invested in
a fund that invested in anthropic. And
then like each of those funds has as
learn how fees compound fees fees and
then so there classically happened with
SpaceX and and there there are a lot of
people just like their returns are
diluted down to nothing or they don't
even know like who's managing the money
on top like above them and like it's a
very dicey game to play. This is why
this is why that we have these highly
regulated public markets at the late
stage because like the bad behavior not
say bad behavior but the lack of
transparency causes real
>> risk but not the kind of risk you should
take in investing like it it's
procedural risk not like actual venture
risk
>> to this money-making point is that like
and it's a point I wish I had known when
I did our I mean it ended up working out
but like I had somebody slide into my
DMs like this year who had an app had
like a few thousand dollars in AR or MR
like but was doing okay was like
starting to take off and was like I want
to raise money. I was like no you do
not. And I asked him, I was just like,
"Okay, so tell me how you sell this
company for a billion dollars." And
they're like, "Well,
this and that, coming up with like
extreme more grasping for straws." And I
was like, "Okay,
>> unless like that is your goal and like
you're going to do nothing but focus on
that outcome, do not raise venture
capital." Like it will all it will do is
like limit your options and make you
miserable and like make your you'll have
mad investors. You know, if you give
good investors, it'll probably be fine.
I know he's going to jail, but like it's
just going to make your life hell. And
luckily, I don't think somebody like
that would probably accidentally raise
venture, right? Like I think it's like
venture capitalists are pretty good at
not making those bets. They can read
that. But like um I do think it causes a
big distraction. I see people like
people like obsessed with applying to
YC. I don't think it's necessarily,
you know, YC is great, whatever, but
they're toolled for you going for that
billion 10 billion hundred billion
dollar outcome. So, like unless like
>> it's not going to be as important or as
effective for you if you're not if
you're not on that trajectory. And back
to your point, Andrew, we've never been
in a better time for somebody to build a
company that like an app company that's
going to make $10 million a year. And
like as a founder, you talk about like
founder outcomes.
>> Like amazing. you've seen it like the
just because your company raised money
and had a bigger outcome and a higher
valuation does not mean you as an as a
as a founder did better.
>> Well, even just understanding like
preferred versus common stock, right?
It's like if you if you raise a $20
million series A, those investors get
preferred stock. If you sell your
company for $20 million, they get all
$20 million. Yeah. Right. Like
>> they get paid first. Investors are
protected are more protected than
founders in downside scenarios. And
depending on the way it's structured, it
could be a 2x liquidity advantage or a
3x liquidity where if you sell it for 40
million,
>> you rarely you rarely see that in 2026
>> in like San Francisco VC, but in like
Austin BC and like in other other
markets, you do still see those kind of
liquid.
>> For the listeners out there, if you get
a term sheet with anything but a 1x
preference, do yourself a favor and
don't take it unless you're desperate.
At the end of the day, you should like
actually believe that you can build a
multi-billion dollar company to go raise
venture because like there is actually
another there's like another credible
path now because like you don't need to
go hire a bunch of engineers. Like you
can vibe code it, be like really
thoughtful about your product and like
you can build a multi-million dollar a
year business with no venture, own the
whole thing and like that's awesome. And
like you have to respect what type of
business it is. It's not just like what
do you hope it could be. It's like some
companies have the
space to become massive if you execute
really well. Others you can execute
incredibly well and they're just still
not going to get that big. So just like
align the capital strategy to reflect
what type of company you're trying to
build
>> and include not just cash capital but
like your time and like not just like
your hours but like the years of your
life. If you're going to spend 5 10
years on something or two years on
something like know what your your
possible best outcome is and make sure
like that's aligned with I won't
disclose too much but I just spoke with
Curtis from Slopes who've had on the
podcast and famously bootstrapped I
think there are like I don't know 12
people now I don't know the company's
and every year he just like reinvests
and keeps going and it's like he's built
a really amazing business and he's very
happy with like how it is right he's
built a great product with a good team
and like they have space to build and
like probably maybe could have done a
venture thing if he wanted to do that,
but like was very conscious. He did a
very like thoughtful and conscious way
of like choosing how to to build that
business. That's the kind of like
thoughtful decision-m people should be
making.
>> To David's point, it can change later,
>> right? Like you can build a $10 million
business.
>> Yeah.
>> And then realize like, wow, we've like
we've earned some insight into where the
multi-billion dollar company actually
is. now we'll go raise to tackle that
and higher valuation less obviously like
your terms are going to be are going to
be awesome but like I think there are
other cases where where it's like hey
we're going to swing we're swinging like
for some massive massive massive thing
like we know the market is huge we know
it's going to be expensive to build and
then sure like go go raise venture is
there a middle path
>> or should there be a middle path though
where like I mean even with my little
bitecoded app that I've been working on
the last three months. Like I probably
spent a thousand plus dollars on my $200
Anthropic subscription and my $200 CHBT
subscription and I put $1,000 into UGC
and like and I wasn't expecting a big
outcome on that, but at at some point
you do need some money. Like these
things aren't free to get the ball
rolling with scaling. You probably do
need 10 $20,000 to to be investing like
and that's on the way low end. Like if
you're going to try and scale paid ads,
you need probably couple hundred
thousand. Like is there a middle road um
for products that are showing traction
but aren't venture scale but can move
fast? Like Curtis, that's a great
example. Like could $300,000 four years
ago helped him shortcut two years of of
slow growth and pain? And like is there
should there be a product for that?
What's the middle road? I think that
there's an opportunity for a new sort of
like venture lane to emerge that takes
advantage of what you're describing or
just a new class of capital necessarily.
>> Yeah, it's just and I and I think it
makes a lot of sense because I think
it's going to be it is going to be a lot
easier for a bunch of reasons for
talented people to build these like
multi million dollar a year apps. And
maybe it's something like small checks
with like a profit share. Like the idea
is to build like a cash flowing business
and it's you know venture is built
around a power law. So like this would
not be a power law.
>> You have to finance your your nine
losses for your one win. That's that's
why venture needs those outcomes because
five five go out of business, four onex
and then one returns all the money.
>> You need mega outliers. But I think that
like I suspect that there's a strategy
around um generating like seeding really
strong developers that generate cash
flowing businesses that aren't going to
require additional capital or like you
know that's not the plan anyway. The
funny thing is those existed and all the
ones I'm aware of actually stopped that
kind of investment in the last like two
to three years. tiny fund, INDVC, com
Fund, three off the top of my head that
were doing almost exactly what you're
saying and maybe they just bailed at
like the exact like moment in when that
curve would have been the right
direction.
>> I don't know. I'd be curious thinks, but
like in in an era where the S&P has been
just on like a generational rip, like
it's really hard to get capital to go
into anything but like treasuries and
the S&P, you know what I mean? Like why
would you bother? And it's not just the
return expectations. It's like how long
do you take to get the return? There's
also the risk. But say you get the risk
right. Managing private investments is
just a pain compared to like just having
your money and your your Robin Hood or
your Fidelity or whatever and like
having some very basic like money
investments like and that's what you're
competing with, right? And even a good
venture fund like a great venture fund,
you know, they 5x the fund in five
years, something like that. That's like
an amazing but like most venture funds
aren't. Those are like the outlier
returns, right? I think in venture if
you can beat the risk-free rate of
return, you're at least like above
water, right? And like a lot of them are
probably close to that. And so it's just
hard like you're those dollars are
fungeible and like you're competing, you
know, unless you just really believe in
the thesis. You like the idea of it.
You're advocacy investing, you know what
I mean? You're investing in something
because you believe in it, not for like
purely capitalist reasons. But at scale,
capital will just flow where capital has
grown the best, right? And so these
things have to like really compete. But
I'm with you, Andrew. It feels like
and I don't know what the structure
looks like because it's is it we have
debt. Does is there like just just are
we looking at like specialty lenders
that like understand these businesses
better? Um
>> maybe it's the RC venture arm.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, yeah, we're talking
about this now. We have daily payouts,
which is like a factoring product,
right? In theory, like we're not far
from being able to build debt based
products where like we loan against your
current run rate. But the thing with
debt is like it's debt. You're borrowing
against your future, right? I guess
there's two differences between debt and
equity like but like debt like you're
borrowing against your future, which
kind of true for equity as well because
when you sell equity, it's like, hey,
you're selling a share of all future
profits. Like when you sell equity, like
you're you're cutting people into a
share of all future profits. The
difference with debt is like the profits
capped that you have to give out, but
but they also have like downside
capture. So like they get your business
if it goes the other way, right? versus
equity is like the upside's uncapped but
the downside is capped, right? And there
are combination products like venture
debt is like a combination product where
it's like it's debt but it's also
includes like some warrants and things
like this on on equity. There's like no
free lunch, right? If something is like
a good return on capital, it will exist
as a venture as a product probably
eventually. If something's not
necessarily a good return on capital,
maybe it won't be my guess. But yeah, I
mean why would something like a revenue
cat like us as a falls in that like
specialty lender, specialty financeier
and like industries have these like I'm
not certain of this but I'm sure like
oil and gas has like specialty banking
that like understands their specific
needs.
>> I'm sure just name your industry there's
like a specialty lender or banking or
investment arm that like helps like
understands these industries better and
can like underwrite them, right? It's
even in venture like venture funds have
their focuses, right? because they can
understand those businesses a little bit
better and make better.
>> It could it could also be just a studio
that adds a lot of value too.
>> Well, actually Bending Spoons is a great
maybe a great example of this, right?
But that's later stage. It's financial
engineering but like plus operational
engineering. It's like halfway between a
private equity fund like roll up and
like an operating company. But yeah,
maybe that exists at the earlier stage.
I don't know. There is an interesting
financing product that I became aware of
just in the last year when ladder used
it is general catalyst growth fund.
That's a really fascinating model.
You've looked into that, right Jacob? So
it it's essentially debt but it's it's
like user acquisition financing where
they fund up to 80% of your acquisition
and then like structurally the way it
works is they do it based on cohorts.
So, like if in January you spend $10
million, they'll finance 8 million of
that and then they track that January
cohort and they get repaid. In their
case, I think it's a only a 10%
annualized interest. They get paid back
out of that cohort's earnings. If that
cohort takes three years to fully pay it
back with the 10% interest, it takes
three years to pay it back. The nice
thing about that is it's one, it's not
diluted funding, and two, it's not a
recourse loan where they're gonna come
take your house
>> or your
>> it's not actually it's not actually debt
in that case, right?
>> It's not an indie putting it on their
credit card where if they get too far
upside down on their credit card, like
they're going to be in trouble. And so
that that is interesting. that one is
only available to much bigger apps, much
more proven, much more, but there's
probably room for that type of a product
to exist on a smaller scale as well.
>> I would be really curious to know, and
this is without any insider knowledge.
Again, it's 10%. It's like why would
they go through all that trouble when
the S&P is making nearly that? You know
what I mean? Like, [laughter]
uh, you know, you got to you got to set
that up. You got to bear there are some
risks involved, right? They could they
take they have to finance the losses in
that interest rate.
>> Well, they set up that fund when
interest rates were only like 3% and now
it's more like 6%. So like thing things
look different like cost of capital is
different, return on investment is
different.
>> General catalyst.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So it's it's it's portfolio
value ad to win deals, right? Like
>> Oh, on the equity side, right? Which
then in that case it's a hybrid product
like like equity plus debt, right? So
almost like a venture
>> venture. I mean I'm not familiar with
it, but that's what would make sense to
me.
>> Yeah, that's what I mean. These things
all like sort of flow to like what's the
risk-free rate of return given a time
and the interest rate like those are
like those really affect these things
which when you're starting out you don't
David it was when you were talking about
like oh I put a couple thousand into
this a couple thousand into that like
you have the benefit of like having seen
like you know scaling an app up and kind
of understanding like the cash flows
there will always be an initial capital
investment needed to get something off
the ground. It is I think precipitously
lower than it was 2 years ago, 5 years
ago.
>> Now that's also because of that
competition has gone up a ton. So like
everything's getting more expensive.
It's going to get more expensive and
potentially like the flow of dollars
you're competing, you know, there's
fewer like I guess that is just
competition, right? Like you're also
competing over all these adjacent
things. So like ad spend, you're
competing over the same eyeballs on the
Facebook networks and all these things.
There's all these like sort of effects.
I have not gone deep on analysis, but
I've been trying to like think about
what is going to happen in the app
ecosystem as this stuff plays out and I
think we've seen it is yeah, there's
like just going to be more competition.
It's going to be tougher. The dollars on
the supply side, I don't think I've
necessarily gone up. I don't even know
if we would have a way to easily see
that. We'll get we'll get numbers from
like app figures and stuff like this
towards the end of the year. Sensor
tower towards the end of the year on
like total consumer spend, but I'll I'll
just say from a naive analysis of our
macro data, it has not seemed that like
spend has rocketed up in in step with
the amount of like new apps we're seeing
be created yet. This sort of comes back
to where we started, which is like
I still think we need better tools to
help people make better products. like
we we brought the cost of building down,
but we need to bring the quality up
>> on average. This has been also why I
keep asking people and I'm like keen to
see because like even if the quality
just stayed the same the and the net the
number went up like let's say we doubled
the number of apps quality stay the same
if you could measure quality by some
abstract number like you would have
twice as many outlier grade apps right
like you would think unless unless I
think
>> the same
>> what right well I mean un to yeah like
that assumes that quality stays the name
which basically assumes that there was
bottleneck on engineering was the only
bottleneck, right? And that like
engineering or like development costs
drop suddenly like all this all this
like excess taste or whatever can flow
into the app store. There's certainly
excess initiative. I'm convincing myself
of your point, Andrew, is that like
there's there's now plenty of
initiative, but is there like is there
like actual ability? Maybe to some
degree, yes, but but maybe not
universally.
>> But I think people can learn certainly.
That's why that's why that's why X1 is
cool because people people can learn.
>> I think everybody who's made a great app
made a bunch of bad apps before that.
>> Yeah. Usually exactly
>> like it's rare that somebody is just
like born there are I'm sure there are
counter examples but like you know it
takes a lot of years of using software
and getting opinions and and and bad
talking to users right like you have to
be able to iterate a ton. So like what
whatever is built has to be set up to be
iterable.
>> Yeah. Which is the case. I mean if the
cost of production has gone down but so
has like the cost of iteration like all
of those costs have gone down.
>> Do you get signal from like average
ratings across the whole app store?
>> It certainly exists.
>> That is actually a very poor measure of
quality unfortunately because so many
apps are gaming it. I mean, this is
actually something Apple just clamped
down on in the last week,
>> which would change the numbers
drastically, right? The fact that
they're
>> apps apps have been and I I mean, I've
had this question for a long time, like
why are all these apps who like seem
like really crappy like why are they 4.9
stars and my indie app that I've like
poured my heart into for a decade is 4.5
stars. And the answer is when you ask in
onboarding and you prompt right, you
just get a volume of people who just
don't even care and hit the five star
and hit submit. So unfortunately the
star ratings are so gamed at this point
that like it's a very poor
>> quality signal. The the one interesting
thing I think Ariel from App figures was
doing this. He he devised some ratios of
the star rating of written reviews. Like
what's what number of onestar written
reviews do you have compared to the
number of fivestar ratings? Because it's
easy to get somebody to tap the little
fivestar thing and hit submit. It's a
lot harder to get them to go like
actually say something good and
meaningful about the product. That's
game to some point too where like people
are still buying reviews and things like
that, but Apple's cracked down on that
quite a bit. So, it's it's harder and
harder to actually fake their written
reviews. So, that that may be a better
kind of signal quality adjustment is to
look at written reviews and and do some
ratios there. I'm glad to hear they've
cracked down on it because at the mine
company, you know, we had some blatant
copycat out of Eastern Europe that
clearly just like bought a ton of, you
know, ratings and reviews and we like
collected a bunch of evidence and sent
it to Apple and they just didn't do
anything. But if they've cracked down on
an hour
>> 3 years later they cracked down on
review farming that's progress. Andrew
is your answer. I think it's like it's
probably just like total spend. You know
what I mean? Like that's probably
probably our best Well, there's there's
you got to like probably per capita
probably like divide that by like you
know humans on Earth or something like
this.
>> I mean it's always it's always retention
though. Like can you see like retain
spend non- churn like churn some
indication of churn? Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, that that'll measure like
that'll measure existing players. The
last two years the answer has been yes,
which is like is there more software
functionality that can be extracted from
phones specifically, but just in general
like personal usage of software like is
there more depth than we had preai? And
the answer is well absolutely yes. Like
I don't know if it's 2x but I feel like
it's a huge increase in like how and
what people are doing with computers
than they were two years ago. And that
was just a factor of all putting making
computers smart and letting them talk
which was is no small feat but it kind
of you know do we think we've hit bottom
like and that was like okay that now
we're actually maxing out what humans
can do with computers it's like probably
not like there's probably more depth to
it will we hit like LLMs were just such
a like step function across everything
like they made everything almost
everything better and faster in many
different ways both in like what's in
the apps but also how they're made and
all all this other stuff. Now, that's
not the same level of innovation that
we're going to have. You again talking
about like a tasteful entrepreneur like
making something that's that's a very
small like needle point like in the in
the total value of apps and humans using
software like as they attack a niche and
they kind of again I I'll go back to ATC
this app I've been really enjoying. It's
a very well done app that like in theory
could have been built a while ago, but
nobody did. And it's like a fresh take.
And I and I have to think that like and
it's doing well in the sense that like I
see it everywhere. People are talking
about it. It's become a thing. And I
have to think that that that's still
possible even in chess like even in like
these like long even in Strava's
category, right? Like I have to think
that there are
>> unique things to say still.
>> For sure. Yeah. Absolutely. But the
chance of finding this is so like
infantesmal that like going back to the
venture thing, it's like that makes it a
very very hard venture bet.
>> Well, it's also just like hard to
disrupt someone else's network effects.
But I'll tell you two things I'm not
worried about. I'm not worried about
like apps not mattering anymore because
everything agents not worried about that
at all. And I'm not worried about
everyone just building their own bespoke
software for everything. But both of
those things have come up as like major
threats or topics or whatever. And I
just think there's no chance of that.
One of the classic mistakes in a
venture-backed business is you get some
company, they're like crushing it,
they're super confident, they're growing
really fast, and then the CEO is like, I
don't like Salesforce. We're going to
build our own CRM and it's going to be
better. You know, and then and then it
becomes like a total boondoggle, right?
It's like this. It's like the same thing
like let someone who's totally focused
on making a thing great make that thing
and then use it and maybe there's like a
more there's like a more there's more of
a personalization layer on top of that.
And I've built software for myself and I
think everyone you know everyone will do
that to some extent and that might drive
down the cost of like buying it off the
shelf which is good I think.
>> Yeah. competes with the incumbent like
the actual
>> commercial. It can't be outrageously
expensive anymore,
>> but like people are still going to want
to use products that other people
create.
>> And then secondly, the form factor might
change, but like people want like
beautiful visual experiences. It's not
only going to be agents talking to each
other, that's going to be like under the
hood, but then people want to people
want to interface with something using
their eyeballs, you know?
>> Yeah. Something that's tasteful, that's
artistic, right? At the end of the day,
somebody was talking about the the the
the Vision Pro and how like if we were
at software maximalism already, like the
Vision Pro had some really cool I've
never actually used one, so I should
shut up. But like had some really
impressive demos, right? They have this
like dinosaur wall demo. There's some
amazing experiences that are like very
short, right? They're very like minimal.
And if we were at true like if AI was
truly replacing like you would have like
these like insanely deep experiences on
these niche platforms, right? And it
doesn't feel like we're there or even
close to there or like anybody's even
working on it, right? The bottleneck
does not seem to be just like purely
like the ability, you know, there's a
lot of pipeline stuff that goes like
we're not at visual rendering
capabilities for like asset creation on
on these things and stuff, but a lot of
bottics still. And to be honest, like
sort of at the beginning of Opus and the
new model wave, I was like, "Oh, kind of
like a software." And like we've we've
seen certainly parts of our software
have become less compelling than they
were pre. But yeah, I mean at the risk
of saying like, "Oh, of course my
business will never be disrupted." But
like I think I've come around to the
same sort of belief.
>> Well, on that high note, let's move on
to the lightning round. There's three
questions I ask every guest when I
remember at the end of the podcast.
>> By some definition, every guest
>> uh what's the most impactful experiment
or change you've seen this year? you
know, not operating apps yourself, maybe
in a portfolio company or across the
industry. What's the most impactful
thing you've seen this year?
>> Okay, I'll give two real quick. I will
give one for myself, which is that I
started building like my own CRM and
like productivity tools, but the
impactful part is teaching them to like
learn and improve. That's what I use Zo
Computer for basically. Like I have a
CRM, I have a to-do list, it's all
connected to my email. I'm not an
engineer, so I'm not going to like blow
myself up like I would using OpenClaw.
But then I actually have it like
evaluate its own performance and get
better on like crafting priority to-dos
for me. And that has been really really
cool. And I'm just like excited to see
what happens in software in general with
those sorts of techniques. And then I
have a portfolio company that built like
their own internal analytics tool that's
just like ridiculously powerful and
anybody can use with natural language.
And so that's one thing on the portfolio
side where I just see the
democratization of like analytical
capabilities within companies is super
super powerful and I think will lead to
like more velocity and better decisions.
So those are two. This is like a whole
another pod. So, I won't fully chase
this rabbit and go down this rabbit
hole. But my biggest concern with the
internal analytics stuff is and I' and
I've heard from people who've had this
issue is like data quality and like the
the relying on the answers you get out
of your internal analytics pipeline is
scary to me
>> for sure. I think you have to put a lot
of effort into making sure it's good,
>> right? So it's like one thing to set it
up, it's another to improve it over time
so that it actually like understands
your data structures and it's you're not
you don't have the garbage in garbage
out problem. But if you can get there,
which I do think is possible, then you
do have a natural language analytics
tool. That's just like like not having
the bottleneck of data analysts and data
scientists or asking like full stack
engineers to like run SQL queries for
something that I think that's a game
changer for companies.
>> I've been using Amplitudes AI for my
product analytics and Rico for my
revenue cat analytics and it's pretty
dang good.
>> We got we got to get all these folks
together. We should have a big chat room
where we add all the agents and let them
talk to each other.
>> All right. What's the worst experiment?
the biggest fail that you've seen in the
past year. I've seen a number of like
security related incidents and I think
this is just a byproduct of like moving
fast with AI. I think people need to be
like conscientious about what vendors
they use as well, right? And like how
are their vendors thinking about
governance? Do they have or is it just
like max velocity ship code? the
industry is going to figure this out and
I don't think the right answer certainly
for a company is to be like oh we're
going to be conservative and like go
slow because you're just going to get
crushed by the competition.
>> Yeah.
>> But I have seen like multiple serious
security incidents that I don't think
would have happened preai. And so I just
think it's something for like general
cognizance and awareness and like
thoughtfulness around the trade-offs
both internally but then also in terms
of like the tools you use and like what
are their what are their principles.
Yeah, that's a really good one. Last
question. Growth would be easier if
>> Yeah. Okay. So, we talked about this
earlier, but I like inference cost
coming down.
>> Like I
like super cheap inference that's really
high quality I think is going to I mean
it's just going to feel unbelievably
magical. And I agree like it does seem
like we're kind of going the other way
right now. I think, you know, probably
the the best models are like we can't
just light money on fire forever. But I
do think, you know, there there's going
to be like more model routing. There's
going to be more building of local
models. There's going to be like better,
you know, physical infrastructure and
all these sorts of things. It's going to
like it's going to come down. I don't
know exactly when or by how much, but I
think that's going to unlock an enormous
amount of growth.
>> Yeah, such a great answer. Thank you so
much for joining. This was super nerdy
but super fun. I don't think we've ever
gone this deep on venture capital before
even like explaining.
>> We had Andrew on twice. We had to do We
did a 101. We had to do a 102. You know
what I mean?
>> So, this is great. I think people take a
lot of value away. So, thank you Andrew
for joining us.
>> Yeah. Thanks for having me. Good to see
you guys. [music]
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.
[music]